SERGIOMARTIN

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - ELECTRONICS ENGINEER

(512) 210 0555 | smartinsantos@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/smartinsantos | http://sergjs.com

-SUMMARY-----

Energetic software & electronics engineer with 4+ years experience developing robust, maintainable code. Enthusiastic team player and deep creative thinker with a can-do attitude, phenomenal time management skills, and a strong user focus. Has developed several web and mobile applications including a cloud base, real-time shared platform for electronic device calibrations.

-WORK EXPERIENCE-----

Web/Mobile Applications Developer @ OnlineMedEd

(Austin, TX) • [04/2017 - current]

- Developed e-learning mobile applications for both IOS and Android Platforms.
- Designed and implemented a system that handles synchronization of offline data between client and server.
- Implemented new features, bug fixes and regular updates in functionality and performance for web based applications.
- Ensured that internal developers/contractors meet the technical standards of the team.
- Provided mentoring to junior developers.

Web Applications Developer (a) InMotion Software

(Austin, TX) • [04/2017 - 04/2018]

- Built complex Interfaces to handle user specific views based on roles and content access.
- Diagnosed errors and performance issues in client side code; proposed and implemented optimizations.
- Created a fully accessible reusable React component library implementing core company designs to facilitate UI development across teams.
- Coordinated response to API outages and product bugs.
- Provided mentoring to junior developers.

Full Stack Web Applications Developer @ WIKA - Calibration24

(Austin, TX) • [03/2016 - 04/2017]

- Architected and developed a cloud base real-time shared platform for electronic device calibrations.
- Responsible for overall infrastructure and running of IT operations.
- Trained and conducted career assessments for new team members.
- Provided technical help to hiring team interviewing potential candidates for engineering roles.

Software Engineer Fellow (a) Hack Reactor

(Austin, TX) • [12/2015 - 03/2016]

- Assisted students as they go through the curriculum
- Conducted one-on-one technical mentoring as needed on a full range of JavaScript full stack web development topics.
- Performed technical interviews for prospective applicants

Engineer In Charge (a) Weatherford International

(Argentina – Mexico – Colombia – San Antonio, TX) • [01/2009 – 09/2015]

- Coordinated personnel teams of 10+ engineers, 30+ specialists, equipment, tools and logistics of field operations.
- Oversaw the preparation and execution of complex electrical logging operations, selecting appropriate methods depending on site-specific constraints and client requirements.
- As Technology Champion, consulted/educated internal and external clients in matters of technologies and their applications
- Monitored operations throughout project lifecycle and responded to customer needs on an asneeded basis
- Trained and conducted career development assessments for engineers and specialists
- Played key role in launching two new business areas in Argentina & Colombia that grew to over \$2mm in monthly revenue
- Built an electronic interface to improve accuracy of well depth measurements, helping save a \$3mm annual contract
- Career progression, Junior Engineer, Engineer, Senior Engineer, General Engineer

Engineer Intern (Thesis Project) @ Tenaris Siderca

(Argentina) • [01/2008 – 05/2008]

- Implemented a continuous monitoring system on a rail crane to prevent safety issues.
- Responsible for designing all mechanical, electrical, and software-driven aspects of the project
- Managed team of 5 and led bidding process for acquiring components and hiring third party vendors
- Engineered control cabinet, setup programmable logic controller, tested electrical components and software systems
- Delivered project at less than 25% of quoted cost, leading to \$860k in total savings for the factory.

EDUCATION——————

MS Computer Science (a) Georgia Tech (Atlanta, GA) • [01/2018 – Present]

Software Engineering Immersive Program @ Hack Reactor (Austin, TX) • [09/2015 – 12/2015]

BS. Electronics Engineering (Automation) @ UNEFA (Venezuela) • [09/2003 – 10/2008]

-TECHNICAL SKILLS-----

- JavaScript
- Node/Express
- PHP/Laravel
- Python
- Java
- HTML
- CSS
- Git
- MongoDB
- SQL

- React
- React Native
- Redux
- Angular
- WebPack
- Gulp / Grunt
- Jest
- Mocha / Chai
- Junit
- Socket.io

- Heroku
- AWS
- Envoyer
- Invision
- Sketch